Hey everyone, I'm Kate.
I've already had a lot of you in the comments asking me to make a video on Qwen 3.7-Max.
to make a video about Qwen 3.7 Max.
So for this video, I've prepared a series of tasks.
to test its reasoning, writing, and programming abilities.
For some of the tasks, I'll have Gemini and GPT models do the scoring.
to give you an objective look at what 3.7-Max is truly capable of.
in the Artificial Analysis rankings,
3.7-Max's score is significantly higher than 3.6-Max's.
making it the most powerful domestic model currently available.
And in my own tests, 3.7 is a huge improvement over 3.6.
3.7 is a huge step up from 3.6.
It also delivered some pleasant surprises when it comes to programming.
First, let's have Qwen tackle a translation task.
The task is to translate a passage into three less-common languages.
Finnish, Icelandic, and Georgian.
Now, even though 3.7-Max is a massive model,
But it's not slow at all.
OpenRouter shows a latency of 1 second.
and a throughput of 69 TPS.
I ran most of these tests late at night.
with a speed of up to 200 TPS.
So, how's the translation quality?
So I had Gemini 3.5 Flash score it.
Gemini gave it a score of 96.
It found that the translation didn't have that stiff, machine-translated feel.
Instead, it was deeply localized and reconstructed based on the distinct characteristics of three different language families.
It listed several key strengths that earned it those points.
Finally, it also pointed out a minor flaw.
Qwen's multilingual capabilities are truly impressive.
And many open-source models support multiple languages as well.
I actually use Qwen's open-source models locally for translation all the time.
The quality is excellent.
Next, I'll have Qwen write a short story of about 200 words.
The requirement is that it has a ton of unexpected plot twists.
At least 10 or more.
And we'll have Gemini score it as well.
And it gave it a score of 95.
It found that the story contained 11 plot twists.
The beginning and end are well-connected, the plot is tight, and it's totally captivating.
Here's the breakdown of those 11 plot twists.
Gemini suggests that one area for improvement is to reduce the use of explanatory language.
The suggestion is that if you could use more objective visual or action descriptions to lead into the twists,
the quality would be taken to a whole new level.
So, here's my advice for using it:
So, if you want to use AI to write a novel for you,
You can have one AI write it, and then send it to another AI.
and pay attention to its suggestions for improvement.
and in turn, polish your own writing skills.
Let an AI Agent help you craft better work.
Qwen is also pretty good for creating slides.
So, if you want to generate a slideshow,
Just remember to select the slideshow tool first.
And then, you can ask your question.
And the final slide images are all generated by Qwen Image.
So, the task here is to have it work with the PDF of the DeepSeek V4 research paper.
to generate a high-quality, easy-to-understand PowerPoint for the general public.
I've always believed that when it comes to slides, content is king.
The design isn't that important.
And to make the content good,
it's best paired with a powerful model.
So, it's the perfect fit for having 3.7-Max generate interpretive slides.
The final slides it generated were highly consistent with the key points of the paper.
Plus, Qwen Image's slide templates have been updated recently.
The background is an off-white color.
Each slide features an illustration and key bullet points.
The use of charts is also very appropriate.
Overall, it's very easy on the eyes.
Next, let's test Qwen's resistance to hallucinations.
Let's have Qwen verify if Einstein won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1938.
in recognition of his prediction of gravitational waves in the theory of general relativity.
Is this information correct?
Qwen didn't use a web search.
It answers directly from its internal knowledge.
In fact, Einstein was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1921.
The reason for the award was his contributions to theoretical physics,
specifically, for his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect.
Qwen's answer is absolutely correct.
Next, I'm going to send Qwen the title of a fictional research paper.
and asked it to look it up.
After searching,
Qwen then searched the 2024 table of contents for the journal Nature Machine Intelligence.
I first conducted a comprehensive search of the table of contents.
It tells me that it has not found any published papers that match the title exactly.
So, these two questions show that for simple questions,
Qwen will draw on its internal knowledge base to answer directly, but for questions that require a search,
it will use a search tool before giving an answer.
Now, let's check out the programming capabilities of 3.7-Max.
I had Qwen generate a mechanical planetarium toy to be placed on a desk.
At least eight celestial bodies orbit a central light source.
Each celestial body should be made of a different material.
And the moment you open the final page it generates...
It's like having a moving mechanical artwork right on your desk.
A brass orrery.
You can drag to adjust the view, zooming in to see the textures of the gears, orbits, celestial bodies, and the tabletop.
Each planet has its own unique material and style.
Some are made of white porcelain.
Some are made of mutton-fat jade, others of colored glaze.
Others are made of obsidian, with a really nice texture.
Clicking on a planet also brings up an information plaque.
You can also adjust the running speed.
Next, let's have it create a music box composition with a visualizer.
The prompt was to use the Web Audio API to synthesize the music box's sound.
When it plays, the notes are plucked by a roller, just like little metal teeth.
and generate light spots and vibrations.
With just one prompt, Qwen got it done.
And it looks really slick.
You can also select a preset melody to play.
You can also clear the entire canvas.
Click to add notes.
You can also choose from six different modes.
I gotta say, the design quality of Qwen's front-end page this time is really impressive.
This task was generated on Qwen Studio.
And we didn't use any front-end optimization skills.
And it wasn't even in 'plan' mode.
And it still pulled it off perfectly.
Next, let's have Qwen generate a shadow puppetry animation editor.
Users can place silhouette props onto the stage.
You can set the position, scale, rotation, and transparency of objects using the timeline.
Let's create a 10-second looping animation.
On the left, we have the prop library.
Elements like the moon, windows, and bridges can be added directly to the stage.
In the center is the stage, which has a paper-like texture.
And on the right, we have the properties panel.
And down here is the timeline.
Select a silhouette.
You can adjust its size, rotation angle, and transparency.
You can also control whether it's on the top layer or the bottom layer.
The key to making it move is the keyframe.
At the 0-second mark, I'll place an umbrella.
Then at the 5-second mark, I'll make the umbrella bigger and add another keyframe.
And finally, at the 10-second mark, shrink the umbrella.
Press play,
And it will automatically generate the transition animation for the zooming in and out.
On the left, you can also adjust the stage lighting and ambient color tones.
It also comes with three preset scenes.
There are presets for a rainy alley, a harbor, and a rooftop. In the rainy alley preset, an umbrella moves from the left side of the screen to the right.
The streetlights flicker erratically.
Plus, it supports importing and exporting JSON, so you can save your finished stages, props, lighting, and keyframes.
You can continue editing it next time.
It's a bit of a shame, though,
Clicking and dragging the silhouettes on the stage doesn't do anything.
Right now, you can only adjust its position using the X and Y coordinates.
But still, to get this kind of result from just a single prompt...
And I'm already pretty satisfied with that.
Finally, let's take a look at a full-stack web application that 3.7-Max helped me build in just over ten minutes.
It generated a full-stack web application for me in just over ten minutes.
Now, the most impressive part of this project isn't actually the front-end page.
but the database, backend APIs, and business logic that run behind it.
I built this application using 3.7-Max in OpenCode.
The entire process took just over ten minutes.
But during those ten-plus minutes, the AI wasn't just slapping together a few buttons and pages.
What really took the time,
was building the backend structure that a real business system requires.
This project is called the Community Festival Booth Planning System.
On the surface, it looks like a simple booth map.
But behind the scenes, there's a complete data flow.
The stall owner submits an application, and the data is entered into the database.
The administrator logs into the backend to review and approve it.
Once approved, the stall can be assigned.
During the assignment, the system also checks for any location conflicts, and whether the spot is near a power and water source.
and whether it's too close to the audience area.
Click on a booth on the map.
You can also see the booth's name, who the vendor is, and its specific column and row.
Next, let's check out the application page.
Here, the stall owner can fill in their name, email, phone number, and the stall's name.
They can select the booth type and enter the required area.
They can also check if they need access to electricity and water.
When I click submit, the front-end will call the back-end API.
and send this information to the server.
The backend will then create a record for the stall owner,
and then create a new record for the stall application.
and set its status to 'Pending Approval'.
Once submitted successfully, the application is added to the database.
It's now waiting for the administrator to process it in the backend.
Next, let's head into the admin dashboard.
Log in with the admin password. When an application is first submitted, its status is 'Pending Approval'.
After the admin approves it, the status changes to 'Pending Arrangement'.
Once the administrator drags it onto the map and assigns a specific location,
the status changes to 'Scheduled'.
Qwen also generated the backend validation rules. For example,
Two booths cannot be assigned to the same spot.
Booths that require power must be located near a power source.
and for booths that might be noisy, like game or exhibition stalls,
and shouldn't be placed too close to the audience area.
Plus, the backend also provides a CSV export function.
The exported spreadsheet contains all the information.
Thinking back to last September,
Back then, I was using the most powerful open-source Chinese coding model to build an app that was way less functional than this one.
It took 5 iterations to get it mostly right.
But now, 3.7-Max got it to this level with just two prompts.
And that second prompt was just to approve the plan and let Qwen get to work.
It finished all the TODOs in just over ten minutes.
And that even included multiple testing stages.
The final deliverables list was also very comprehensive.
So, what about the code quality?
But just watching a demo of the features might not give you the full picture.
So I had GPT-5.5 xhigh give it a review.
So, GPT's overall evaluation of this project is...
For a demo prototype generated by a large AI model in just over ten minutes,
The demo is a prototype.
The level of completion is quite good.
So, if I had to rate it...
Demo completeness: a 7 out of 10.
For production readiness, I'd give it a 3.5.
out of a possible ten.
GPT acknowledges that Qwen has achieved a complete functional loop.
The tech stack is well-chosen, and constraint validation has been abstracted into a separate module.
It has a testing mindset.
The UI is highly demonstrable.
The issues include the fact that the admin backend has almost no real back-end authorization.
There's no strict validation for things like email format, string length, or phone numbers.
The CSV export has issues with data formatting and security vulnerabilities.
And I basically agree with the issues GPT pointed out.
and that's what led to these issues in the code.
And I have to admit, I was also largely to blame.
After it generated the plan, I didn't review it carefully and just had Qwen start coding right away.
If the requirements you give it from the get-go are too broad,
So naturally, that's going to affect the final outcome.
So, my advice is, when you're actually using it, make sure to align the requirements with the model first.
and then have it start coding.
I also took a screenshot of the TODO list from Qwen's coding session and sent it to GPT.
I asked it to evaluate whether these TODO items were properly completed.
And GPT scored each item as well.
So, let's see what its strengths are.
and which areas still need work.
In actual programming,
So, having multiple models review each other's work is still absolutely essential.
Even a powerhouse like GPT-5.5
and having 3.7-Max review the code during the process,
you can get some unexpected rewards.
And that's all we have for Qwen3.7-Max today.
From my experience, the Qwen Max model has improved significantly.
Officially, its strengths are said to be in programming, office productivity, and workflow automation.
as well as long-term autonomous execution.
And right now, Qwen3.7-Max is 50% off for a limited time.
I'm really looking forward to the Max model getting visual capabilities soon.
I hope you found this video helpful.
See you next time.